all right welcome to the
office hour of cs6300
i am shin and here's paula
hi everyone and in case
you don't know it's
office hour it's week 14.
somebody told me we didn't
know last week that you
weren't here so somebody
kindly said it's week 13 so
now i came in remembering
this is week 14. but i might
be i might be wrong yeah
it's actually a week 14
so um week wait wait wait
is it um april yes week week
14 right so this um week
14 out of 16 weeks of uh
is it spring semester yes
spring semester so in this
week students have no more
lesson and and are working
on individual project
deliverable three and by the
way if you have even though
it say no lesson if you
are late on the lesson please
make sure that you watch
all of them so that you
won't get any point deduction
for the participation so
just a friendly reminder
other than that yeah IPD3
is going strong I think
and with that um we will
get started with the office
hour even though we don't
have any questions yet so
with no questions then okay
so Because I see there is
an answer is you cannot ask
question here. So if you
have any question, you need
to go to the post about
the office salary net and
post your question there.
And we will read it and respond
directly. We have
the page open.
But was this some privacy
issue, right? The reason why?
For a part issue.
I should have known
because I did the
training, the renewal
of the training,
probably late, two
weeks late, last
week. Oh, yeah, I'm
also two weeks late.
But it's always the
same one. I don't
understand. Nothing
ever happened.
The compliance one,
yeah, it's more like
reminding you,
reminding the employee.
And also it's more like, I
think we are recording, so
I have to watch my
language. but it's more like
covering the institution in
case of things hey i already
do the duly regions and
then best effort and but i
wish they asked you the
question at the beginning and
if you can if you can answer
you don't have to watch
the videos instead it's the
other way around you need
to watch the video to be
able to answer the question
oh true which is i think
you know like it's kind of
you asked the prerequisite
at the beginning and it's
not letting me type in the
in the chat of the office
hour okay so since this is
my first office hour post
did I mess it up no somebody
wrote something so no
okay it's correct Thomas so
Thomas say it doesn't let
me yes you need to post
your question exactly where
you post your comment it's
not let me so wherever you
post the comment in the ad
posting which you say it's
not let me type anything
in the chat of the office
hour that's correct this
is how the office hour work
so you cannot you cannot
type in this chat and you
cannot speak in this chat for
for regulation that actually
protect your information
from other students um
in general like we we we need
to protect your information
from people that are not
supposed to receive them
and so you can post your
question in the discussion
wherever you put
the comments i know
it's a little
cumbersome but it's for
good reasons anyway
uh continue our
oh yeah the question is
okay sure yes go ahead
just write it down and
we will respond yes
um well meanwhile i
continue our podcast so i
think that the uh the
compliance i mean the the
legal compliance hardly
changed but the security
compliance i think is
worth uh changing every
year because of ai and
right now and then i even
i mean even this year when
i do that the training
is a lot of things about
AI phishing already.
So in that case, I
mean, yeah, I'm more
receptive to why it's
kind of mandatory.
Yeah, no, no. You know, like I
have nothing against training,
but I find curious that we
are still all doing this
training that are always
the same format. You listen
to a video, you answer to
some question, you listen to
a video, you answer to
some question. And on the
other hand, there is all
this research that is exactly
on the other opposite of
the spectrum of people doing
vr for hands-on training
and i mean and which is
which i think is very is it
makes total sense in certain
contexts right like you
know conversation in an uh
on a um operating room that's
make total sense because
you know like how you
communicate it's better if you
train in virtual reality
or in emergency situation
but there is nothing in the
middle right like you know
people will not do VR
training for privacy and
security in their company.
But what is in between that
video that is comprehensive,
but is, I don't know, is
this the best format? Also,
I feel there should be
something in between those
two extremes, right? The usual
format and the super
-evoluted format that makes
sense when the end part of
this becomes more relevant.
Okay, I think we have
the question now for A6.
Probably it's
about MCDC, right?
Yes, let me pull
up the solution.
When he said it, let me share
my screen. not the screen
but I the document nobody
really wants to see my screen
yes okay here it is okay
can you see my screen Shin
yes you are the only person
who can respond to me so
okay so if we are here okay
and assuming because the
question is about the choice
of the number of test cases
and not so assuming we are
okay on how we arrived to
this table right that we
explained last week And we
arrived to disable in a way
that we have to cover all the
couples that are couples
in which just the condition
in the row is the one that
changed and nothing has
changed, but that change in
that condition make the final
result changing. right so
for instance if you look at
uh row two and row six uh
the only thing that changes
the true value of c equal
to zero and the total result
uh change right because in
in the the decision in the
decision in the this um in
the graph is in a case true
in a case false right so
assuming and And then if this
is not the case, Thomas,
please feel free to cover.
Assuming we agree
on how we found this
pair, as I explained
it last week,
now what you want to do is to
cover each of
these pairs, right?
And so you have no choices
for C equal to 0 and D
greater than 0, then pick 2,
6 and 2, 4, right? you don't
have any other choices
because there is just one pair
that cover these two specific
conditions so you are
taking row two row four
and row six that means with
any of these three with
two four and six you cover
something between one and eight
right and so it also means
that you need to to cover
a equal to zero you need
to pick something in nine
and between nine and sixteen
any of them it's the same
so assuming we are picking
uh nine okay now we already
picked two four six and
nine how do we cover e less
than zero you have many
different ways since you
already took four you can decide
to take three and so you
have three and with three
four you are covering also
this condition or you can
decide since you already
have six to take five and so
you have two four five six
nine but there are always
six so the minimum that
you they're always five the
minimum that you have to
take is five of course if you
take six you're still
covering all the condition but
if you strategically should
so for instance you can say
i pick two six two four and
seven eight and then and
then and then you still need
to pick nine sixteen and
so you have an extra one
um do i make any sense yes
yes okay thumbs up let
me unshare my screen i
think i was not in the
office hour last week but
did we also talk a little
bit about the the shortcoming
of mcdc and given the
same kind of logic someone
can cheat the mcdc um
cut up the the metrics by
moving um moving the the
logic to a variable and then
you set variable as is in
in the um in the condition
you want to see the screen
again um I mean yeah
if you can share if you
can share that of course
answer a six yeah you
are again right so
for For example, now
in, let's say and or,
remind me the,
the. Okay, this is
the code. Okay,
look at the. Yeah.
You have this simple condition
here, and then if it's
true, you go here, you
have this very complex one.
Right. And these
are your options.
and the um for example
in the if c equal to
zero and d more than
zero and a less than zero
for example if we remind
me the the n operate the
n operand is um yes so
you do c equal to zero and
the d greater than zero
first and then or less
than zero right so um for
example here, if somebody
refactor the code and have
the, let's say, T equal
to, and then the analogic
C equal to 0 and D
greater than 0, So that T
itself is a Boolean value,
right?
And then we replace
that T into this.
You can control the
content of the presenter.
Stop control.
Yeah,
did you get it? Because my
computer is complaining.
um i just want to uh to
get me my mouse moving
um on your computer
yeah i know i'm trying
does it work now i should
never mind no because
it wants me to restart
the app so it's not that
no no never mind um i
mean if if we if we move
that c equals zero if we
extract c equals zero and
D greater than zero into
another variable and
then replace that variable
into this condition,
then we kind of remove
the total number of MCDC,
of the test cases
required for MCDC,
even though it's
logically the same.
I see what you're saying.
No, we didn't, we didn't, we,
Will and I had a long
discussion on the fact
that he likes to see the
code more than the control
flow graph and he said
like, no, it's just,
no, Oh, the control
program is so much clearer.
Anyway, this is... Yeah,
well, actually, that's
the point, right?
Because when we refactor
that, the control graph
kind of changed as
well. Because at that
time, in the node here,
it's only one
condition, variable T.
It's no longer C and
D. So it's kind of
collapsed. even
though the input to
this unstable method
4 remains the same.
Thomas,
have something more?
Is it more of the why
wouldn't A and B consider
different conditions?
Since A is different from B,
it's the same as the XOR B.
C and B are volume 1.
Maybe I should stop
unsharing this solution,
because before I
share something
else, okay, so
let's put it back,
the code, right now we
need to see the code,
A and B are two boolean,
if A is different from B,
a different from b is true
if they are different so
if one of the two is
true just one yes i mean
conceptually yes because
basically what you're asking
is that at least one of
the two that exactly one of
the two is one and the
other is zero so it's just
conceptually it's the
same thing because
you need for this
to be true one
has to be true and
the other false it's
uh uh it is more of that
why wouldn't a and b because
am okay so okay uh i didn't
see this comment right
because at some point you
say it is more than uh of
that why would an A and
B considered a different
condition? Because in reality
the condition is just one.
It's true or false
depending on the combination
of value of A and B,
but it's not independent
from those values. So it
doesn't really matter,
you need to look at A
and B together because
the condition is one,
is A different from B.
And so it's exactly
one in in this case.
The meaning of that is
that exactly one of the
two can be true at the
time for this to be true.
But it doesn't matter, because
you see this as the condition
is just one.
They don't influence them.
You see them as variable,
not as condition, just
because they are Boolean.
but they say i'm good before
i say this so i hope i
didn't confuse him more
okay but he says good great
okay i've stopped sharing
this time hopefully it's the
doesn't have to be the last
one but here it is okay
so uh another um another
uh comment set Another
question. Victor said
that I did what she is
saying and I only needed
the fewer than five test
cases. I refactor my table.
Is it possible that I
could get full points
with fewer than five test
cases? How can you refactor
the table? You can,
what I described is that
when, only when you,
when you refactor the
code, but the instruction
of the assignment is that
given this code, you,
the students are expected
to file on the test
case. So you are not
allowed to change the
code or refactor the
code. I mean, if you are,
if the instruction
allows you to refactor
the code, then yes it
could be but then in
this case that is the
instruction does not so
that is a good news that is
the bad news I'm sorry and
by the way technically I
mean if if we are going to
that refactor route technically
people can just refactor
all the condition into
the variable before the if
control flow. So it will
collapse into a trivial MCDC.
How did I refactor the
table? When I did the
manual table to see all
the condition of multiple
nested gates and the
norm, the table flattened
and pure condition changed
with combined logic.
Manual tables on the
condition of multiple
nested, the table flattened.
Well, the thing is you
cannot flatten the
table, the truth table in
here, right, because of
the definition of MCDC.
So, yeah, so Victor
already thumbs up, I see.
I just want to explain
again, the problem
or the discrepancy
here is the, let's say,
I would say flaw, but
then not strictest
definition of the MCDC.
So that's why people can
find the loophole
or the workaround by
changing the code or
changing the control flow.
But given the
same control flow,
it's the same
truth table anyway.
We have a new question.
Now that IPD1 has closed,
can we get some more
insight on what exactly
we should have covered?
Were we expected to
get full coverage of the
test scenario in IPD2
with the test cases created in
IPD1 to get full
credit on IPD1?
Were we expected to get
full coverage of test cases?
No, IPD1 and IPD2, they
are created separately.
ipd2 is built on
top of ipd1 meaning
that if you were
doing a perfect ipd1
you would have a
better starting point
coming into ipd2 that
doesn't mean that
you have to do
perfect in ipd2 it
in order to get
ipd1 full score so
back to the original
question can we get some
insight what exactly
we should have cover
um i'm not sure what
this question is about
because um what still the
the rubric coverage for
ipd1 is different from
ipd2 i'm not sure whether
you are asking what uh
what um student should
have cover for D1 or
D2. For D1, well, we
cannot disclose right
now because as mentioned,
subsequent deliverable
is built on top of D1.
So if we disclose on the
expectation right now,
it will give students
unfair advantage. So we
can only do that when
the whole IP is closed.
As for D2,
it is automatically
graded, so you know it as
soon as Grayscope is
finished, so you know
whether you already cover
90% of all the cases,
in which case you
already get full points,
and if students actually
get 100% cases covered,
then students even get
the bonus point okay
I think that's pretty
much it so I think
we can call it oh
one more question
for IP D3 is it
okay to copy some
code from the helper function
on the test class
we use for D2 helper
function I'm not
sure how per function
what I mean if it is
the code written by
yourself then of
course you can reuse if
it's a code written by
download in the template
yes of course you
can reuse it as well
function to open files
yeah because it is
provided to you by by
the class by it is a
cost material so you
you can use it without
without needing to
do any citation okay
that's it i think
right so if that's the
case then thank you all and
because we are now in the
daylight saving time i hate
changing uh the clock but
it's um more time to enjoy
in the evening especially
those with the family
or small children like
myself so especially those in
the west coast because the
air is already dark all
right right so um yeah enjoy
the evening and see you
on it and next week bye
everyone thank you shin bye